<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cmakepp on toeb&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://toeb.github.io/tags/cmakepp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cmakepp on toeb&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://toeb.github.io/tags/cmakepp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>cmakepp: Template Generation in CMake</title>
      <link>https://toeb.github.io/post/cmakepptemplategeneration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toeb.github.io/post/cmakepptemplategeneration/</guid>
      <description>Find it at http://github.com/toeb/cmakepp
Download cmakepp standalone file here
As with all my work I appreciate all feedback given and am particularly happy about virtual internet points 🙂
To the Post: While working on the documentation of cmakepp I grew wary of always doubling the documentation – one in the source code and a mirror in the README.md. Also I was frustrated when I refactored and renamed functions or changed signatures which is not uncommon – especially when working on a new feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful extensions for CMake</title>
      <link>https://toeb.github.io/post/usefulextensionsforcmake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toeb.github.io/post/usefulextensionsforcmake/</guid>
      <description>When using cmake for more than just simple projects it is lacking in various aspects. Some list and string functions are missing. Interaction with command line applications and the file system are harder than they need to be. Especially however using structured data (maps and objects) and more complex funtional programming is not easy at all. So a couple of months ago I started implementing some extensions for object oriented programming 1 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cmakepp: Reading and Writing JSON</title>
      <link>https://toeb.github.io/post/cmakereadingandwritingjson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toeb.github.io/post/cmakereadingandwritingjson/</guid>
      <description>While working on a package manager for CMake I came across the problem of finding a suitable format for my package descriptor files. First I thought about and tried using plain old CMake file that simply sets variables and can be included to access its contents. It was very quick and easy to implement. Hierarchical data structures however where hard to implement and a none standard format makes it harder to exchange data with a webservice/other programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Oriented CMake: Next Iteration</title>
      <link>https://toeb.github.io/post/objectorientedcmakenextiteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://toeb.github.io/post/objectorientedcmakenextiteration/</guid>
      <description>I worked on my object oriented extensions for CMake and am on a much higher level of usability than before!
try it at https://github.com/toeb/oo-cmake
and as always: Feedback is most welcome
See the following object tutorial for ease of use: (for the current version look at the readme.md on github)
### using objects ### ============= # oo-cmake is very similar to javascript # I actually used the javascript reference to figure out how things could be done :) # oo-cmake is a pure object oriented language like javascript (only objects no types per se) # oo-cmake is currently file based and relies heavily on dynamic functions to be upfron about it: # oo-cmake is very slow (depending on what your doing) ## creating a object ## ================= obj_new(myobject)# ${myobject} now is a reference to an object obj_exists(${myobject} _exists)assert(_exists)## deleting a object ## ================= # oo-cmake does not contains automatic memory management # you can however remove all objects by calling obj_cleanup # (a very crude way of garbage collection) I would suggest calling it at the end of cmake.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
